This is the summary of my work
这就是你让我
and my work plan
分管内容的阶段性总结
for the next phase.
跟我下一步的工作计划
Looks good.
挺好的
Your thoughts are clear,
思路很清晰
and goals, too.
目标也很明确
Through my observation of you
我通过这段时间
during this period,
对你的观察
I've noticed
我发现
that you are someone who is
你是一个有计划
goal-oriented
有目标
and has strong execution skills.
且执行能力很强的人
Thank you for the recognition.
谢谢总监肯定
Actually,
其实现在这些
these tasks
工作内容对我而言
are pretty basic for me.
是向下兼容的
After this period
经过这段时间
of getting familiar with Xinmiao,
我对新苗的熟悉啊
this is what I think,
我是这么想的
Director,
总监
I want to, while completing
我想在完成
the tasks you've assigned me,
您给我的这些
also push forward
工作内容的同时
the tasks assigned by Mr. Zhang.
也推进张总给我的任务
Is that okay with you?
您没问题吧
No problem at all.
没问题啊
Mr. Zhang already approved it.
张总不是都同意了吗
The point is, can you handle it all?
关键是 你忙得过来吗
This workload is
现在这点工作量
nothing compared to that when I was
相比我在蓝海
the Content Director at Blue Ocean.
做内容总监的时候
It's a piece of cake.
小意思
But I heard recently
但我听说最近
that the overtime work is piling up.
加班量有点大啊
Did someone
是有人
complain to you?
找许总监抱怨了吗
No, they wouldn't dare.
那不是 他们也不敢
They're all young people.
都是年轻人
What's wrong with working more overtime?
加班多干点怎么了
They gain experience that's beneficial
积累的工作经验
to their development.
是他们自己的呀
It's good for their growth.
对他们自己的发展
Right?
有好处
Yes.
是
But as leaders,
但是我们作为领导嘛
sometimes,
有时候
we need to consider
还是要顾及一下
everyone's feelings.
大家的情绪
Understood.
好的
I'll keep that in mind.
我有数了
But, Director Xu,
但是许总监
actually, Mr. Zhang
其实张总
only cares about results in the end.
他最后也是只看结果的
So when it's time to push hard,
所以该拼的时候
we have to push hard.
还是得拼
Wouldn't you agree?
你说呢
Sure.
拼吧
Did you take in
我跟你说的话
everything I just said?
你都听进去了吗
This company isn't just yours.
这公司不是你一个人的
You have to be responsible
你得上对得起股东
to the shareholders and employees.
下对得起员工
Look at your
你看看你现在
current work state,
这个工作状态
slacking off half the time.
三天打鱼两天晒网的
Is this acceptable?
这能行吗
Chairman,
董事长
excuse me, I need to take a call.
对不起 我接个电话
Mengxin.
心
The baby keeps crying?
孩子一直哭啊
Why is that?
为什么呀
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
find me a nanny right away,
你赶紧给我找个育儿嫂
a certified one, understand?
有证的那种 听到没有
Okay, okay, I'll do it ASAP. Honey.
好好好 我尽快 心
Don't worry.
你放心
I have something to do now.
我处理点事
Okay.
好
Think carefully about what I said.
我说的你好好想想
I'm leaving now.
我先走了
Chairman,
董事长
stay for dinner before you go.
吃完饭再走吧
You know what?
你呀
You better go home for your wife.
还是回去伺候老婆吧
Most people marry
别人娶老婆
for a supportive wife.
是娶个贤内助
But you, you married a goddess
你倒好 娶个菩萨
to worship.
供着
Chairman, the main point is...
董事长 主要
Having a baby isn't something
这女人生孩子
that happens often in a lifetime.
一生也没几次
But isn't she off work right now?
那她不是不上班吗
She can't even take care
一个人在家
of the child at home all day?
带孩子还不行
She had a C-section.
她是剖腹产
Recovery's not going well.
恢复得不太好
You take maternity leave.
你生孩子休产假
But the executives at other companies
可其他公司的老总
aren't taking time off.
可不休产假
Listen,
我告诉你啊
if you miss
你要是错过了
this opportunity,
这一波风口
don't blame our partners
可别怪我们的合伙人
for pulling the rug out from under you.
釜底抽薪
Since everyone chose you
既然大家选你
to be the general manager,
当了总经理
you're responsible
你就得对
for their money.
大家的钱负责任
Goodbye, Chairman.
您慢走啊
Bye-bye.
董事长 慢点啊
What are you staring at?
看什么看
What opportunity did I miss?
错过什么风口了
Why wasn't I informed?
我怎么不知道
You missed the last board meeting.
上次董事会您没在
I sent you the minutes.
会议备忘录我发您了
You could've sent them again.
你不会多发几次啊
I've been reminding you non-stop.
我一直提醒你来着
By the way,
对了
here are the materials
这个就是
from that last meeting.
上次会议的那个资料
Fine, I'll look them over at home.
行了 回家我自己看吧
Mr. Jia,
贾总
there are a few documents
这还有几个文件
that need your signature.
需要您签
Later. Don't bother me right now.
回头再说 你烦不烦啊
Please don't forget!
您 您可记着点啊
Unbelievable!
不会吧
What's wrong, kiddo?
怎么了孩子
There. There.
不哭 不哭
She pooped!
拉粑粑了 拉粑粑了
Gotta clean up.
得去洗洗啊
I can handle it.
我可以的
Ma'am, I've sanitized my hands.
太太 我消过毒了啊
Okay.
好
Alright.
行行行
I'll do it, I'll do it.
我来 我来 我来
Here, here.
来来来
Be careful.
小心 小心
Got it.
好的 好的
Let's go.
走走走 快去洗
Hurry up!
赶紧 赶紧 赶紧
Good kid.
好乖 好乖
There. There.
宝贝 不哭了啊
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
don't come home tonight
今天你不找到育儿嫂
unless you find a nanny!
你别给我回家
Got you some bubble tea.
给你买的奶茶
Thanks.
谢谢
So, how'd it go?
怎么样啊
Nothing to say.
无功无过
If we have a fight,
要是一战
she would be the loser.
手下败将
Then start competing!
那就卷起来呀
Not gonna happen.
不卷
Her main job right now
她现在最重要的任务
is to help me transition smoothly.
是帮我平稳过渡
If I start competing with her now,
我现在跟她卷
how am I supposed to have a baby?
怎么回家生孩子
I've got an idea.
我有一个想法
I'm not sure if I should say it.
不知当讲不当讲
Tell me!
你快点讲
You can't hold it back.
一会儿憋死了
I'll suggest to Mr. Zhang
我去跟老张建议
to split the Content Department
把内容部
into two parts
拆分成两个部分
and have Huang Sisi focus on
让黄思思出去
expanding new business,
拓展新业务
so she doesn't resort
以免她用不正当手段
to underhanded methods to take over.
鸠占鹊巢
As for you,
你呢
you just need to stick to your turf.
就守住这一亩三分地儿
How does that sound?
怎么样
The Content Department was just merged.
内容部刚合并
Can we really split it now?
能拆吗
History shows that what's long united
天下大势
will eventually split, and vice versa.
分久必合 合久必分
You have to adapt to the times.
你得适时而定
If we separate her out,
把她分出去了
she'll be independent.
她独立了
She'll make her own decisions.
自己说了算了
She'll definitely agree.
肯定能答应啊
What do you think of this plan?
我这想法怎么样
It's not a bad idea.
也是个办法
I'm pretty sharp,
我这脑子
it'd be a waste not to be a boss.
不当老板可惜了
Just let me chill.
你还是让我躺平吧
What's wrong?
怎么了
High risk in Down syndrome screening.
唐筛高危
High risk?
高危
Look at my doll.
看我这个娃娃
See?
你看
Even though yours is golden,
虽然你那个是金色
mine is a bit pinker.
但是我这个更粉嫩一些
Definitely from a good store.
肯定是从好商店里买的
What do you think?
怎么样啊
Do you like
爸爸买的礼物
daddy's gifts?
喜欢不喜欢
Yes!
喜欢
Thank you, daddy!
谢谢爸爸
What would you
待会儿想吃点
like to eat later?
什么好吃的
I want pizza.
我要吃披萨
I want to go home to see mommy.
我想回家见妈妈
Sis,
姐
now that you mention it,
你这么一说
I miss mommy a bit too.
我也有点想妈妈
But look,
不是 你看 这这
every week daddy only has
每周爸爸就这么一天
this one day to see you.
能见着你们
Daddy misses you all the time.
爸爸平常这么想你们
Don't you miss Daddy?
你们就不想爸爸啊
But mommy is home alone
可是妈妈一个人在家
and has no one to have dinner with.
就没人陪她吃晚饭了
Actually, 85% of
其实百分之八十五的
marriages
婚姻啊
can be saved.
都是可以挽回的
Just utilize the resources of marriage.
利用婚姻的资源
For example,
比如
you can create some
去制造一些
heartwarming moments
父母和孩子在一起
between parents and kids.
温馨美好的画面
How about this?
要不这样吧
Let's get some pizza first,
咱们先去买披萨
and then go home
然后回家跟
and have dinner with your mommy.
跟妈妈一块儿吃
How does that sound?
好不好
Great!
好 好 好
Alright!
那好 那咱们就
Let's first get the pizza,
先去买披萨
then head home.
然后回家
Sounds good?
好不好
Wonderful!
好
Don't worry, it's not porridge this time,
放心吧 这回不是粥
or noodles.
也不是面
It's a healthy meal I made myself.
是我亲手做的健康餐
Quinoa salad.
藜麦菜
Dr. Yu,
俞医生
I'll clean the lunchbox and
我一会儿吃完
return it to you after I finish eating.
把饭盒洗干净还给你
Thank you, you're a great neighbor.
谢谢你 中国好邻居
We should use an outsourced team
咱们用外包团队组
to cut costs.
降低成本
Labor costs
人力成本
are our biggest operating expenses.
是我们最大的运营成本
Yes, it reduces costs.
是 这降低了成本
That's quite good.
是挺好的
But this...
但是这
This outsourcing...
这外包吧
I still feel a bit uneasy about it.
我还总是有点不太放心
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗
It's about quality control.
就是质量把关上
I feel...
觉得
Meng'an.
梦安
Director Xu.
许总监
Am I interrupting?
是不是打扰你们了
No, not at all.
没有 没有 没有
Come in, come in.
快来 快来
Just in time to try the tea
正好 尝尝那个思思
that Sisi gave me.
送我的新茶
No need.
喝不了了
I'm here to ask for leave.
我来找你请假的
I have a prenatal checkup.
有个孕期产检
I might need to go.
我可能得去一下
It will take three days.
需要三天
What kind of checkup?
什么检查呀
It takes three days?
这一查 查三天
High risk in Down syndrome screening.
唐筛高危
I might need to do a surgery.
可能要做个穿刺手术
That's serious!
这可了不得 你这
Three days? Is it enough for you?
不是 三天够吗
Should be enough.
应该够了
At your age... Jesus!
这年龄大呀 我跟你说
Sit down, Director Xu.
坐 许总监
During pregnancy...
这怀着孕就是
I can't sit.
不坐了
Pregnant women...
孕妇
It's not good to sit for long periods.
坐时间长了也不行
Meng'an,
梦安
I want to tell you,
我跟你说啊
you've been working
你这段时间
too hard lately.
确实太辛苦了
With your two deputy directors
你这两个副总监
in place,
都到位了
you can delegate
你有什么活
tasks to them.
就交给她们干呗
Your main job is to protect your fetus.
你现在最大任务就保胎
We'll handle the work.
对 活我们干
Director Xu, please take more rest.
许总监 你多休息
Okay.
好
Well, um...
那那 那个什么
Sisi seems to have something
思思好像有点事
to discuss with you.
要找你商量商量
I think Director Xu
这件事我觉得
will definitely support this matter.
许总监肯定支持
Alright, you can talk.
那行 你们聊
Baby, please stop crying.
宝贝啊 你别哭了
What's wrong?
这怎么回事 这是
Let me handle it.
我来 我来 我来
Is she hungry?
她是不是饿了呀
How could that be?
怎么可能
She was fed just an hour ago.
一个小时之前刚喂的
So,
那她是不是
she wasn't full earlier?
刚才就没吃饱啊
Mom.
妈
Do you always think
你是不是永远觉得
I don't have enough milk
我奶水不够
and my daughter is hungry?
饿着你孙女了
No, no, absolutely not.
没有 没有 绝对没有
Hey!
不是
Please don't cry.
不哭了啊 不哭了
Honey.
小西瓜
What's going on?
这咋回事
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文
I...
我告诉
Why are you crying?
哪儿不舒服这是
Hello.
西瓜妈妈
Shanshan?
珊珊姐
Please come in.
快 快 快
Please.
快请进
Mr. Jia asked me to come here.
是贾总让我来的
You finally arrived.
你可算来了
Why is the baby crying?
这小西瓜怎么哭了
I'll take a look.
我去看看啊
Okay.
好
Shanshan?
这不珊珊吗
Shanshan.
珊珊
Hello, Auntie.
阿姨好
You finally arrived.
你可算来了
Here.
快 快
Let me take the baby.
给我 给我
Check it out.
你快看看
What's wrong with the baby?
这小西瓜怎么了
Just cannot stop crying.
这老是哭
Why?
为啥呀
Baby.
小西瓜
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文
You're something.
你可真行
Mom! Mom!
妈妈 妈妈
Mom! We're back!
妈妈 我们回来了
Coming!
来了 来了
Be careful, be careful.
小心 小心
Babies.
宝贝们
Mommy!
妈妈
You're back so soon.
这么快就回来啦
What's the matter?
怎么了 这是
You're sending them back already?
这就送她们回来了
Why not spend more time with them?
不多陪陪她们呢
I want my doll!
我要玩具
Well...
那个
Here. Take them.
拿着 拿着 拿着
They wanted to eat with me,
这既想跟我一块儿吃饭
but also wanted to see you early.
又想早点见到你
So I thought,
我一想
why not just pack it up?
那干脆就打包吧
Let's eat together.
咱一块儿吃
Right?
对吧
That's better.
那多好啊
Honestly,
我跟你说
the girls are very considerate.
这孩子太懂事了
It's because of your good upbringing.
这都是你教育得好
I know you don't like pizza,
我知道你不爱吃这披萨
so I bought seafood porridge for you.
所以我给你买了海鲜粥
Do we have bowls at home?
那个家里边咱有碗吧
Stop!
回来
Change your shoes.
换鞋
Mommy!
妈妈
See?
你看
The doll you promised me.
你答应给我买的玩具
Daddy bought it for me.
爸爸给我买了
Yes!
对啊
Alright, you can play in your room.
行 那你们回屋玩吧
I'll talk to dad for a moment.
我跟爸爸说几句话
Okay.
好
Don't rush.
慢点
What's wrong?
怎么了
Yu Hai.
于海
Don't buy things for the kids
你以后不要
randomly in the future.
给孩子乱买东西
I originally wanted to
这玩具 我本来是
buy the dolls
想作为奖品
as rewards for them.
买给她们的
But with you doing this,
可是你这样的话
it makes it hard for me to educate them.
我很难管理她们
Children at this age
这么大的孩子
are especially good at taking advantage
特别会利用
of conflicts between their parents
父母之间的矛盾
to achieve their little goals.
达到她们的小目的
Is that so?
是吗
Children these days
现在孩子们
are so scheming.
都这么有心机了
To prevent them
那咱们
from taking advantage
为了不让她们
of it again,
以后再得逞
let's resolve our conflicts.
咱俩把咱俩之间
How does that sound?
这矛盾解决了 好不好
Resolving the issue is simple.
解决方式很简单
Next weekend,
就是下周末
you don't need to come over.
你不用来了
Well...
不是
No, no, okay.
不是 那 那好
Then I won't buy them
那以后我
anything in the future.
不给她们买东西了
Alright?
行吗
We need to resolve our conflict.
咱们该解决矛盾
We should resolve it, right?
咱解决矛盾 对吧
You can't just
你不能就这么
simplistically and arbitrarily
这简单武断的
resolve the person causing the conflict.
你就把这产生矛盾的人
Right?
给解决了 对吧
Check it out, right here.
你看 这 这里面
See? They've even got bowls in here.
它 它有碗啊
The bowls at home are clean.
家里碗干净
That's right.
是
Give it a try. See if it's good.
你尝尝好吃不
Smells pretty fresh.
闻着挺鲜的
Their food
他们家东西
is always amazing!
就是特别特别香
I knew you'd like it.
我就知道你肯定喜欢吃
If you like it, go ahead and eat.
你喜欢吃你吃啊
It's not that. I'm just worried that
不是 我是怕
if you enjoy it too much,
万一一会儿你吃高兴了
this serving might not be enough.
这一份不够
There's another serving here
这儿咱还一份
for you.
都给你
Can you stop talking so much?
能不能少说话呀
It's really affecting my appetite.
很影响我的食欲
Wanwan, Zhenzhen,
婉婉 真真
come out and eat some pizza!
出来吃披萨
Mom,
妈妈
I want to play a little longer.
我想再玩一会儿再吃
Wanwan, come here.
婉婉 过来 过来
I'm coming!
来啦
Mom.
妈妈
The doctor brought you
医生叔叔又给你
more goodies!
带好吃的了
Here.
来
Take the pizza inside
把披萨 拿进去
and eat with Zhenzhen.
跟真真一起吃啊
Okay.
好嘞
Don't get it on your clothes.
别弄衣服上了啊
Got it.
好
See you later, Mom.
妈妈 待会儿见
What's this broccoli?
这西兰花是什么东西啊
Look, are these raw or cooked?
你看这生的熟的
Unbelievable!
这这这
The cutting board
人家分没分这
isn't even clean.
案板都不知道
You may get a stomach ache.
你别吃完之后再拉肚子
Let me throw it out.
我给倒了
Do we have a plunger?
咱家有皮揣子吗
I told you the broccoli isn't good.
我说这东西不好吧
Even the toilet won't eat it.
你马桶它都不吃
Yu Hai.
于海
Are you here to deliver food
你是来送饭的
or to cause trouble?
还是来添堵的啊
What?
什么
Are you crazy?
你疯啦
Who told you
谁让你把办
to give the office to her?
让给她的
Calm down, calm down.
消消气 消消气
Unbelievable!
不是
Outsourcing team?
什 什么外包团队
That's just an excuse!
就是一借口好吗
She's only been at Xinmiao for a few days
她才来新苗几天呀
and already thinks she's all that,
觉得自己翅膀硬了
right?
是吗
Let her come and see me!
让她来找我
Listen,
我告诉你
Nobody can move into your office!
你办公室谁也不许动
How could you let her get away with this?
反了她了还
Hey.
不是
Mr. Zhang always said
那张总都说
I should share the office
让我跟她
with her.
一个办公室去了
What could I do, not let her?
那我能不让吗
No way!
让什么让
She can't move in!
不能让
Who is she!
她什么级别 什么待遇
I'll get it covered!
这事归我管
Let me talk to her!
我找她去
No!
不不不
Don't go!
你真不能去 真不能去
Listen to me.
你听我说啊
If you go now,
你现在去
it will be seen as obstructing
那就是阻拦
Director Huang's project,
黄总监的项目
and Xinmiao's content upgrade.
阻拦新苗的内容升级
We can't take the blame for this.
这锅 咱不背啊
Besides,
再说你看我
look at me.
现在这个样子
I'm in no shape to do anything.
我还能干什么呀
I've thought it through.
这事我都想明白了
What I need to do now
我现在要做的
is to support my subordinates
就是尽最大能力地
to the best of my ability.
支持下属
It's just an office.
不就是个办公室吗
It's not like it's home.
又不是家
Let her have it.
让就让呗
As long as it's good for the company.
对公司好就行了
But...
不是
It's just...
这
Meichuan.
美川
Director Xu.
许总监
I heard you're moving.
我听说您要搬家了
How about
要不
I help you pack?
我帮您收拾收拾吧
Pack my foot!
收拾个屁
Hey, hey! Meichuan.
不是 那个 美川
She...
她她她
She just broke up
刚交的男朋友
with her boyfriend.
跟她提分手了
She's in a bad mood
心情不好气
and is taking it out on me.
在我这儿撒气呢
Alright, if you need help,
那行 那您需要帮忙
just let me know.
跟我说
Thank you.
谢谢啊
I haven't even had a boyfriend yet.
我还没交男朋友呢
Don't curse me like that.
你别这么咒我
Don't be like this.
你别这行不行呀
It was a slip of the tongue, sorry.
口误了 口误了
Calm down.
消消气
I can't.
不行
I need to talk to Mr. Zhang.
我还得找张总说道说道
This kind of bullying isn't right.
不该这么欺负人的
There's some good news.
有个好事
Do you want to hear it?
想听吗
What is it?
怎么
You're moving into his office,
让你搬他办公室
and he's promoting you to vice president?
升你副总裁了
How is that possible?
那怎么可能呢
Come.
来来来
Sit down.
坐着说
If he asks me to go to his office,
再说 他让我去他那儿
I can't go either.
我也不能去啊
Why can't you go?
你怎么不能去啊
You should be sitting across from him.
你就应该天天坐他对面
Pester him to death.
膈应死他
If I sit across from him every day,
我天天坐他对面
how will I slack off?
那我还怎么偷懒啊
This isn't good for the pregnancy.
我这 不利于安胎的
I told him
我跟他说
I want to move to your office.
我去你那儿
We'll be in the same room.
咱俩一屋
He agreed.
他同意了
What!
你
Hey!
我
You...
不是 你
It doesn't do me any good!
你别分我蛋糕呀
What...
不是
If you go to my office,
你去我办公室
the sunlight there is poor.
我那儿日照短呀
My place is cluttered with stuff.
我那儿东西又多
And...
它
It's small.
不是 我那地方又小
People come and go...
每天人来人往的
Going there isn't good
你去我那儿
for your pregnancy either.
它也不利于你安胎呀
How about setting up
那要不你在窗户边
a workstation by the window?
给我安排一工位
You...
你
You're so pathetic.
你也太窝囊了
Don't throw kitchen trash
以后厨房垃圾
in the toilet ever.
不要扔在马桶里了
Thank you.
谢谢啊 师傅
So comfortable.
真舒服
Dad.
爸爸
Where else are you feeling pain?
你哪儿还疼
My neck hurts.
我脖子疼啊
Anywhere else?
那爸爸 你还哪儿疼啊
I...
我
My whole body's hurt.
全身都疼
Let me help you.
那我帮你揉一揉吧
Wanwan, Zhenzhen,
婉婉 真真
you gotta go to school tomorrow.
明天要上学了呀
Go check
你们去把那个作业
your homework,
检查一下呀
and pack your school bags.
快把那书包收拾收拾啊
But dad is hurting all over.
可是爸爸他全身都疼啊
I'll take care of him.
我给他治
Alright.
好吧
Go.
快去
Thanks to both of you for the massage.
谢谢两位按摩师啊
Yeah.
好
You've done a great job.
辛苦了
It was nothing.
一点都不辛苦
Look,
不是 你看吧
this is probably
我这个
due to sitting at a desk
可能是平时这个
for too long.
伏案工作的时间太长了
So,
所以这个
my neck and back
脖子呀 后背啊
are really stiff and hurt.
都不太好
That's why I bumped into the door earlier.
所以刚才我才会撞门上
Just use a pain patch.
贴个膏药就好了
I'll have some delivered.
那我要个外卖膏药
Can you help me apply it?
你帮我贴一下呗
My arms are
我 我 手 手短
too short to reach.
我够不着
Right, just put it on from the top.
对 从上面也行啊
A bit lower.
再往下点
Right there.
就这儿 就这儿
That's good.
就这儿
Perfect.
行 贴这儿行
In the future,
这以后啊 什么这个
don't let any outsiders
物业的呀 保安的呀
like property staff, security guards,
还有这什么
or food delivery people
送盒饭的这些人
into our home.
别让他们进咱们家
Just three of you in this house.
就你们三人在家
I would be worried.
我不放心
Why?
有什么不放心的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You are all smiles!
笑得这么开心啊
A professional nanny
这专业的月嫂
really makes a difference.
可就是不一样啊
Look, Shanshan knew immediately
你看珊珊一来就知道
that the baby's crying
这小西瓜
was because
是因为屁股红了
of the bottom sore.
才哭的呀
It was because you and Yingzi
还不是你和英子
didn't clean her properly.
给她擦屁股
You made her bottom sore
把屁股擦红了
and she cried all afternoon.
哭了一下午
And you thought my milk wasn't enough
非说我奶水不够
and she was hungry.
把孩子饿着了
I didn't realize
我哪儿知道
babies' bottoms
现在的孩子的屁股
could be so sensitive these days.
都这么娇贵啊
Alright, alright.
行了 行了 行了
No need to make a fuss.
这有啥好说的嘛
Shanshan is doing great.
珊珊现在不是
She helps a lot.
让我们给挖过来
It's nice to have a professional
多好 咱们家
take care of things.
一下就踏实了
I'm going to get some nursing oil.
我去拿护理油
Sure.
好
Honey,
媳妇
I really handled this well, didn't I?
我这事办得漂亮吧
Cost a lot?
很贵吧
Whatever the cost,
多贵都值得
it's worth it.
专业的人办专业的事
handle these things.
专业人干专业事
Don't worry about the cost.
妈 你别老惦记着钱
I can cover it.
儿子给您挣回来
Don't be so tight-fisted.
别抠抠搜搜的
Honey.
小西瓜
Let's have some oil.
我们擦香香喽
Here, let me help.
来 我来 我帮你
Thanks.
谢谢
No worries.
没事的
Is that enough?
够不够
Enough.
够了 够了
See?
看看
She's smiling.
笑呢
You are so professional.
这手法真专业
Shanshan.
珊珊
Teach me someday.
你有空你教教我哈
I want to help as well.
我也得学学
Sure thing.
没问题 阿姨
Why, mom?
妈 您学啥
You want to do this?
您还给她擦油啊
With your rough hands,
手那么糙
I don't think so.
再剌着我们家闺女
Fine.
真是
So rude.
净嫌弃我
Feel good?
舒服了吧
See, she's enjoying it.
你看她多享受
See?
看她舒服的
Impressive.
真是的
Don't touch her!
你别摸
Why? I'm her dad!
我怎么不能 我是她爹
Babe...
宝宝
Give me more of this.
再来一点
Okay.
好
A bit more.
少来一点
More.
再来点
Raising kids these days
这养孩子啊
is so much more scientific.
真是越来越科学了哈
There's real progress.
真进步了
When I was young,
我小时候您咋养我的
you didn't have any of this.
啥都没有呢
Now you complain.
嫌弃我
Look how much she enjoys it.
你看她多享受啊
Really, she's so comfortable.
真是 好舒服的
I heard from Grandma
我听外婆说
that you've been drinking chicken soup
你最近都跟你妈
with mom lately.
喝鸡汤啊
Yes.
是啊
Every day, it's just plain boiled chicken.
天天都是清炖白煮
Am I postpartum?
我又不坐月子
I don't like it neither.
我也不喜欢喝
My aunt has been making it for my mom.
最近我大姑也给我妈做
Jesus...
吃得我呀
I can't even swallow it.
嘴里一点味都没有
Let's go out for a nice meal today.
咱们今天去吃大餐
What do you want to eat? It's on me.
你想吃什么 姐请你
I'm ok with anything.
都行 你看着办吧
I love everything you like.
反正你爱吃的我都爱吃
Great, let's have a feast today.
行 咱们今天吃顿好的
Hey, can I borrow some money?
姐 你借我点钱呗
I want to buy this card set.
我想买这套卡牌
This?
这个啊
I'll buy it for you.
姐给你买啦
Really?
真的
Thank you!
谢谢姐
You are welcome.
客气啥呀
Our middle school students' allowance
我们中学生的零花钱
is definitely more generous
还是比你们小学生
than yours.
宽裕些的
I hope I'll have that much
希望我上了中学
when I'm in middle school.
有这么多零花钱
You definitely will.
那肯定啦
You'll probably have more than me.
到时候你肯定比我多
Hey, do you think my younger sister
姐 你说小西瓜将来
will have more than I do in the future?
会不会比我的多
No way. You're the eldest.
怎么可能 你是老大
You'll have to
到时候 你必须
take care of your little sister
像我照顾你一样
just like I do.
照顾妹妹
Got it?
知道吗
I'm your role model.
我可是你榜样
Why don't we team up now?
要不咱俩现在就搭伙吧
I'll learn from you.
我好好向你学习
You can share my snacks.
你管好我零食
You can learn from me.
向我学习可以
But your snack? It's a no-go.
管你零食就算了吧
Kids shouldn't eat too many snacks.
小孩不能吃零食
That's what the "health expert" says.
这可是养生专家
My aunt, I mean.
大姑说的
Being a kid is so tough.
做小孩好可怜
I wish I could grow up like you tomorrow.
好想明天就长你这么大
Oh, Zhenzhen,
对了 真真
let's use our dolls
我们用娃娃
to play house!
来表演一下吧
How?
表演什么
Let's do this.
那就玩这个
Sis,
妹妹
look, I'm the queen.
你看 我这是女王
Better than you,
比你那个
you are just a small princess.
破公主可厉害多了
I'm a princess.
我这个还是公主呢
I'll be the queen one day.
公主还是女王的继承人
Time's up.
时间差不多了
Then I won't allow that to happen.
那我不让你继承
I'm your daughter.
我可是你亲生的
Yu Hai.
于海
I'm talking to you.
我跟你说话呢
Can't you hear?
没听到啊
Your ears aren't working,
你这耳朵也不好使
huh?
是吗
You step on me? I would step on you.
怎么被你踩了 我要踩
It's getting late.
时间不早了
They need to take a bath.
她们得洗澡了
Fine.
行吧
That
你那个
is definitely made up of mirrors.
肯定用镜子做成的
must be really hard.
那个
Well, dad's leaving.
那 爸爸走了
Hey!
不是
Dad's clothes are here.
爸爸衣服在
It's like dad's still here.
就约等于爸爸在
Okay?
好不好
Fine.
好
Look, dad's on the balcony.
你看爸爸就在阳台上
And
然后就
I'm standing there.
爸爸就在那儿站着
Well,
这个
that means your guardian
你们白天呀 晚上
is here with you all day.
都可以安心地在这儿玩
Just play and sleep freely.
安心地在这儿睡觉
Alright?
好不好
Yeah.
好
Just take dad's clothes
爸爸衣服
as a scarecrow.
就像稻草人一样
You are always with us.
一直守护着我们呢
Yeah.
对
Exactly.
没错
I'm leaving.
爸爸走了
Just go.
赶紧走吧
How can I live without you?
没你我该怎么活啊
I'm leaving.
爸爸走了
Enough.
没完没了了是吧
Just go.
赶紧走了
Goodbye, Wanwan.
拜拜婉婉
Goodbye, Zhenzhen.
拜拜真真
Goodbye, Wanzhen.
拜拜婉真
The lunchbox delivery guy...
送盒饭的
He won't be as charming as me.
能有我这待遇
Goodbye, girls.
拜拜了
Enough.
行了 行了
What are you two doing?
你们俩干吗呢这是
Haven't act enough?
还演戏
Who taught you this?
你这跟谁学的呀
Go clean up. Take a shower.
赶紧收拾收拾 洗澡去
Okay.
那好吧
Hey.
回来啦
I'm home.
回来了
Where's Yunjie?
云阶呢
She went to play with Xiongxiong
去找熊熊玩去了
Meng'an is pregnant now.
梦安现在怀孕了
You need to keep a close eye
云阶的学习问题
on Yunjie's studies.
你要抓点紧
Don't let her play around all the time.
别老让她傻玩了
Got it, got it.
知道 知道
I've been keeping an eye on it.
一直都在抓
Wait.
来来来 别走 别走
Come here.
过来 来
Take a look.
你看
You've got it ready!
弄好了
Yes!
是啊
Look, I've also made a booklet.
你看 我还弄了个册子
You can use this
你们去医院产检啊
for the hospital check-ups.
拿着这个就行了
You are really something.
还得是我姐
Meticulous
做事啊讲究
and careful.
仔细
Alright.
行嘞
I'll go do it tomorrow
那我明天就去办
Tomorrow?
明天就去啊
Sure.
得早点去
There are many people
现在去医院建档的人
waiting to do this.
还挺多的
Fortunately, I went to the community today
那今天幸亏我去社区
and got all the paperwork done.
把手续办全了
That's right.
那可不是吗
Let me tell you.
我跟你说啊
Look.
你看
This receipt
这个单据
is from Meng'an's first blood test
就是梦安第一次抽血
when she found out she was pregnant.
发现自己怀孕的单据
You need to keep this safe.
这可得保存好
Sure.
行
And this.
还有这个
This is from the community.
这是社区给的
Child health care manual.
幼儿保健手册
Okay.
好
Take these.
你把这些拿着
You gotta
产检的时候
bring them to the check-up.
这些都要带上
If you don't have time,
你要没有时间
I can go with her.
我可以陪着她去
No.
不行
I need to do this.
这事得我去
Sis.
姐
Alright.
好好好
You go, I won't argue with you.
你去 我不跟你争
Lin, I want Meng'an
临临 我想让梦安
to go to the hospital
要不然到梦心
that Mengxin
生孩子那个医院
to give birth at.
去生吧
I think that hospital
我觉得那个医院
has good conditions.
条件挺好的
Yeah.
是挺好
But it's a little bit expensive.
就是贵了点
I'll have it covered.
我出钱
It's not about money.
这不是钱的问题
Meng'an is an older mother-to-be.
梦安是高龄产妇
If anything goes wrong...
这个万一有什么事
..it's better to be in a public hospital.
到了公立医院
I'd feel more secure.
我心里会比较踏实
Right?
对吧
You are right.
也对啊
But...
不过
Looking at these documents,
从这些单据上来看
I don't think there's anything
我觉得没什么事
to worry about.
你别瞎操心啊
She's having a second baby.
都二胎了
There shouldn't be any issues.
不会有什么事的
Yes.
是
I'm not worried.
我不操心
Usually, everything's fine.
一般没啥事
Definitely nothing to worry about!
肯定没啥事
Yeah, definitely nothing!
对 肯定没啥事
Now you are talking.
是
What's wrong?
怎么了
If mom and dad were still here...
要是爸妈还在的话
..they'd be so happy to hear
知道你有老二了
you're having another baby.
肯定会特高兴
Why are you crying?
这这这 怎么哭上了呢
Look at you.
你看看
You're moved.
自感啊
Feeling emotional.
自我感动啊
I'm just so happy.
姐是高兴的
I know, I know.
知道 知道
Alright then.
行了
I'm cooking.
我去做饭了
Okay.
行
Right.
好
Thank you.
辛苦你啊
I'm so happy.
姐高兴
This is a limited edition card!
我这是限量卡
I'm so lucky!
发达了
Mine is a special edition too.
我这也是隐藏款
We hit the jackpot.
咱们运气太好了
Cheers!
干杯
Sis, you're so good to me.
姐 你对我这么好
I'm not used to it.
我都不习惯了
Haven't I always been good to you?
我以前对你不好吗
Well, you...
你以前
...always used to play with my mom.
都跟我妈妈梳小辫
Is it because my mom
是不是我妈现在
has no time to be with you?
没空和你玩了
No, not at all.
什么呀
I just thought you were feeling down.
我是看你闷得慌
Since Auntie hasn't been home
之前小姨两个月
for two months,
没回家了
I figured you missed her.
你不想你妈呀
Sis, if you take me out for BBQ,
姐 你要是请我吃烤肉
I wouldn't miss my mom so much.
我就没那么想了
Look at you!
瞧你那点出息
Alright, we're having Korean BBQ tonight.
行 咱今儿韩式烤肉
Cheese platters.
芝士铁板
Let's go!
走起
Having a sister is the best.
有姐姐真好
It really is.
有姐姐好吧
I'm so happy
我真替我妈
for the baby
肚子里那个宝宝
in my mom's belly
感到幸运呀
to have a great sister like me.
有个我这么好的亲姐姐
You won't stop liking me just because
你不会有了亲弟弟
you have a younger brother, right?
就不喜欢我了吧
Of course not.
怎么可能
You're still my brother.
你可是我老弟弟
And besides,
再说了
who knows,
说不定
the baby in my mom's tummy
我妈妈肚子里那个
might be a sister.
是妹妹呢
I like sisters anyway.
反正我喜欢妹妹
Me too.
我也喜欢妹妹
I'm the big brother to my younger sister.
我也是小西瓜的大哥
When she grows up,
等她长大
I'll play with her, like you do with me.
我像你这样 带她玩
Then I'll be
那我岂不是
the biggest sister
率领三个小孩的
leading three kids! Cool!
大姐头啦
I've got
我下面也有
two younger ones too.
两个弟弟妹妹了
Auntie's baby
以后大姨生了宝宝
gotta call me big bro.
也得管我叫哥
Have you finished your homework?
作业写完了吗
No eating until it's done!
写不完不许吃饭啊
I'm doing it right now.
我马上写
That's right.
小样
Hold your head up higher.
头抬高点
That won't be good for your neck.
都钻进去了
Honey.
老婆
Don't brush your teeth before bed.
睡觉前先不要刷牙
Drink the milk first.
把奶奶喝了
No.
不喝
You make me drink milk and soup all day.
整天让我喝奶喝汤的
I'm gonna throw up.
我要喝吐了
Honey, honey, honey.
老婆 老婆 老婆
Just take a sip. Just a sip.
喝一口 喝一口
It helps you relax and sleep well.
安神 能睡好觉
Finish it.
喝完
Come on.
喝完 喝完 喝完
Honey,
我跟你说
I'm going back to work
明天啊
tomorrow.
我回单位上班去啊
What about the baby?
那孩子呢
Aren't you taking care of her?
你不带了
I'll handle everything alone?
我一个人管啊
Honey, isn't Shanshan around?
老婆 不是珊珊在呢吗
She's a professional.
专业人士
She's here for professional support.
她负责专业陪伴
I'm here for emotional support.
我负责情绪价值
Honey,
老婆
don't touch me. I'm so frustrated.
别碰我 烦着呢
Why should I stay home with the baby
凭什么我一个人
while you get to work
在家带孩子
and relax?
你上班躲清闲啊
Honey,
老婆
I don't get to relax either.
我哪儿敢躲清闲啊
See, I'm here with you
你说你生完小西瓜以后
for over 50 days
我陪你坐月子
since you have given birth to the baby.
都坐了五十多天了
Workers at my company
单位的人说
are all complaining
这不行啊
about me.
老不来上班
Like, what's going on with Jia?
这老贾怎么回事啊
Honey,
老婆
see,
再说
I'm also working to support our family,
我上班也是给咱们家
I mean, to create wealth.
创造财富
What do you mean?
你什么意思
You create wealth outside,
你在外头创造财富
and I stay home doing nothing?
我在家里吃闲饭 是吗
Honey,
老婆
you are the greatest asset we have.
你是咱家最大的财富啊
You're my everything.
你是我的命
I don't believe that.
信你个鬼
Honey,
老婆
just have one more sip.
再喝
Madam. Where should I put this bed?
太太 这床放哪儿啊
Just put it there for now.
你先放那儿吧
Why are you setting up a bed?
搭个床干什么呀
Aren't you trying to create wealth?
你不是要创造财富吗
Then you go ahead and create it.
那你去创造呗
Shanshan and I will sleep here.
我和珊珊睡主卧
I still need to feed the baby at night.
晚上还要喂奶呢
Where should I sleep then?
那我睡哪儿
Sleep wherever you want.
你爱睡哪儿睡哪儿
I understand.
我明白了
My wife loves me so much,
我老婆太爱我 心疼我
she's worried about me
怕我自己
that I might not sleep well.
睡不好觉
She wants me to sleep alone, right?
专门让我自己睡 对吧
But dear, let me tell you,
但是老婆 我跟你讲
I'd still prefer to sleep
我还是愿意跟小西瓜
with you and baby.
跟你睡在一起
It's so much more intimate.
这样多亲近啊
Isn't that right, dear?
对不对 老婆
Sorry.
对不起
I don't want to be close to you.
我不想跟你亲近
Go.
走吧你
Honey.
老婆
Dear.
走走走
Honey, the milk.
老婆 喝奶奶
You have it.
你喝吧
You need to create wealth,
你要创造财富
so you need to sleep well.
你得安神
Dear.
老婆
Thank you.
辛苦你啦
Madam?
太太
What happened?
这 咋了
Nothing.
没事 没事
Just set up the bed.
你把床支上吧
Okay.
好好好
Son,
儿子
why aren't you sleeping at this late hour?
这大晚上的 不睡觉
What are you doing?
你干吗呢 你啊
Mom, you scared me.
妈 你吓死我了
Why aren't you sleeping at this late hour?
您大晚上还不睡
What's going on?
干吗呀
Did Xinxin kick you out?
被心心给赶出来了吧
Mom, what are you talking about?
妈 您说什么呢
Isn't it because your daughter-in-law
这不您儿媳妇
is worried about your son?
心疼您儿子吗
She doesn't want me to take care of
不舍得让我晚上带孩子
the baby, and I also have work to do.
这不还有一堆事呢吗
Is that true?
真的假的呀
Mom, don't interfere in our matters.
妈 您以后别掺和
It's between us.
我们俩事
I won't interfere, I won't interfere.
不掺和 不掺和
Mom.
妈
I'll go to my mother-in-law's place
我明儿去老丈母娘家
tomorrow to bring Xiongxiong here.
把熊熊给接回来
You take care of the eldest grandchild.
您好好在家带大孙子
Don't trouble her.
别惹她
Got it, got it.
知道啦 知道啦 你这
Where are you going, mom?
你干吗去妈
Xiongxiong's pants are torn.
熊熊的裤子开线
I'm going to sew them up.
我拿点针线给他缝上
Where did you get the needle and thread?
哪儿来的 拿什么针线
Acting so virtuous...
把自己还整得贤惠的
Go to bed.
赶紧回家睡觉去
Go to your room.
下自己屋去啊
Fine.
行行行
Be careful going down the stairs.
下楼梯慢点
Alright.
不拿 不拿
You should rest early too.
你也早点歇着
Got it, got it.
知道了 知道了
Don't fall.
别摔着啊
Okay.
好
Be careful, hold on tight.
慢点 扶好
Got it.
知道了
You drop me off
你一会儿把我送到医院
at the hospital later.
就把我放下吧
Then you can go to work.
然后你就去上班
I took the day off.
我请了假了
I've been with you for every check-up.
哪次产检不陪着你啊
Not today.
今天不用你陪
Today's
今天
check-up might take a bit longer.
产检项目可能有点多
There might be a lot of tests.
时间会有点久
Just do your work.
你该忙什么忙什么去吧
Why is it going to take a while?
为什么要有点久啊
You're not hiding anything from me,
你不会有什么事
are you?
瞒着我吧
No.
没有啊
You better be honest with me.
你最好说实话
Well...
说实话
Just...
就 就是
I got a message from the hospital,
我收到医院发的信息
saying my Down syndrome screening is abnormal.
说我唐筛指标有点高
I need to have surgery today.
今天要做个穿刺手术
When did you find out?
什么时候的事
Yesterday.
昨天
Why didn't you tell me?
那你为什么不告诉我呢
You didn't tell me about something so big.
这么大的事你不告诉我
Can you handle this
这种事你一个人
all by yourself?
能扛下来吗
What if something goes wrong?
万一出了问题
You should have told me.
你也不告诉我
It's a surgery!
它穿刺手术 它
It's a big deal!
它也是个手术嘛
Unbelievable!
这这这
I'm just scared.
我不是害怕吗
Well, if you're scared,
那 那你害怕
you should tell me.
你就得告诉我嘛
What do you think of me?
你把我当谁了
No worries.
没事
I'll be here with you.
老公陪着你
It'll be okay.
不会有事的
Haowen.
浩文
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
Honey!
媳妇
You are awake?
你醒啦
Why are you sleeping here?
你干吗睡这儿啊
I was working.
我 我这弄工作
I must have dozed off.
给睡着了
Are you trying to play the martyr?
你跟我卖惨是吧
Can't you sleep in Xiongxiong's room?
熊熊那屋不能睡啊
I was up three times last night
我昨天一晚上
feeding the baby.
起来了三回喂奶
You, on the other hand,
你倒好
slept through the night.
一觉睡到大天亮
I can't even wake you up.
叫都叫不醒
Being a man is so easy.
做男人怎么这么容易
Honey.
媳妇
I know you're hungry.
我知道你饿了
I'll get you something to eat.
我给你买吃的去
Why didn't you do it earlier?
你早干吗去了
You're getting it now?
你现在买
I'll be starving to death when you home.
买回来我都饿死了
Yingzi.,
英子
is there any food?
有吃的没啊
I'm starving.
我饿死了
Yingzi, hurry up with the food.
英子 快整点吃的啊
I just talked
我刚才和大夫
with the doctor.
咨询了一下
The doctor said
大夫说啊
there are many possible reasons
这个唐筛指标有点异常
that lead to abnormal results.
有很多的原因
The surgery is
为什么要做这个穿刺呢
to further check
就是进一步地排查
if it's related to chromosomes.
是不是和染色体有关系
And since you are an older pregnant woman,
再加上你是高龄产妇
it's quite common.
这种现象很普遍
Really?
真的吗
Why would I lie?
我骗你干什么
Aren't you nervous?
那你都不紧张一下吗
Of course, I'm nervous.
我紧张啊
I am worried about you.
我紧张的是你
I don't know if there's anything else
不知道你多少事
that you haven't told me.
你瞒着我呢
I'm sorry, okay?
我错了还不行吗
Just stay calm.
你放松心态
Relax, don't be nervous.
放轻松一点 别紧张
If you're nervous,
你一紧张
the check-up might not go well.
一会儿检查了又偏差了
So, relax.
是不是
Don't worry.
放松
Mrs. Xu Meng'an. Time for the surgery.
许梦安女士 准备手术
Go on.
去吧
I'll wait here for you.
我在这儿等你
Stay calm.
放松点
You're letting me go alone?
你就让我一个人去吗
Come on.
来 走
Our company's project
我们公司这个项目呢
is focused on providing shared equipment
主要是服务于小型的
and technical services
创业公司的
for small startups.
共享设备以及技术服务
Next month, on the first,
下个月一号
we'll have
在我们的工作室
a small launch event
有一个
at our studio.
小小的一个发布会
If you're free,
希望大家如果有空的话
come by, chat,
过去聊聊天
and have some tea.
喝喝茶
Maybe
说不定
we'll spark
我们之间能碰撞出
some new ideas.
一些火花呢
This club
这个俱乐部啊
was set up
是圈里的几个
by a few investors in the circle.
投资人搞的
Though it's called a club,
说是俱乐部
it's really more of
其实就是一个
a matchmaking service for investors.
投资圈的婚介
It hosts small venture capital meetings
搞一些小型的创投会
to help projects
给一些项目呢
find potential investors
搭一个能找到
and stuff.
投资的鹊桥
I find the communication here
我觉得这里的沟通效率
is much more efficient, compared to
比那些大型创投的
large venture capital events.
高多了
Plus,
而且都是
the projects are all carefully selected.
精挑细选的项目
Many of the business models
好多商业模式啊
are quite innovative
都比较新颖
and very promising.
而且很有潜力
Wendy,
温蒂
are you interested in any of these?
有没有感兴趣的
Yes.
有啊
I've noted them down. Take a look.
我都记下了 你看看
I think these
我觉得呢
align well
这和我们公司
with our company's
投资的方向
investment direction.
比较契合
We can proceed
可以进行下一轮的
with further research and contact.
调研和接触
Looks like
看来咱俩是
we're on the same page!
英雄所见略同啊
I also think these options are good.
我也觉得这几个不错
You have a knack for thinking like a boss.
所以我说你有老板思维
You're too kind.
过奖了
There are more meetings this afternoon,
下午还有几个创投会
but they might run quite late.
但是能到挺晚的
I'm not sure how long you can stay.
我不知道你能到几点
You're the boss.
你是我老板
It's up to you.
你说了算啊
Well, I'll have to take you out more often
那我以后可要多带你
to broaden your horizons.
出来见见世面了
It's free of charge.
反正又不花钱
These are opportunities
这可是花钱
that money can't buy.
都买不来的机会
That's right.
没错
In our field,
干咱们这行呢
once you're in,
只要入了行呢
having the skills is essential,
业务能力是必须的
but ultimately,
但最后拼的就是
it's about vision and perspective.
眼界和格局
So,
那你觉得
if I want to become
我现在想成为一个
a good investor,
好的投资人
what do you think my shortcoming is?
短板是什么
Your shortcoming is
你的短板
you have
就是
no shortcomings.
没有短板